Alexander Cochrane

alexcochrane.ca

Alexander Cochrane

14 Edwin Ford Court Bedford, NS B4A 4B6

+1 902 452 2539

alex.g.cochrane@gmail.com

Overview

As both a software developer and a musician, I value creativity and know the success of a project or performance relies on connecting with the client/end user/audience. I like figuring things out, being creative, troubleshooting and coming up with ways to improve code and ultimately improve the end-user experience. I believe collaboration, teamwork and idea sharing are key to ongoing professional development.

Education

Nova Scotia Community College / Information Technology - Programming

Graduated June 2018

Learned multiple programming concepts and languages (Java, PHP, Javascript, Python, C++, C#, etc.).

Used version control softwares (e.g. git).

Created UML-style diagrams for design of programs.

Nova Scotia Community College / Music Arts

Graduated June 2014

Learned about the history of music, and the theory behind playing. Practiced individually and in ensembles, and performed recitals in both formats.

Studied the business of music, as well as the wider topic of entrepreneurship.

Skills

Programming Languages: C, C++, C#, CSS, HTML, Java, Javascript, PHP, Python, SQL, XML

Tools: Eclipse, JetBrains, Visual Studio, Xamarin Studio, XCode

Operating Systems: *NIX (Linux, BSD, etc.), MacOS, Windows

Mobile Application Development: Android, iOS, Windows 10 Phone

Self-Directed learning: Unity Game Engine

Experience

Big Brothers Big Sisters of Greater Halifax / Web Application Development Project

APRIL 2018 - JUNE 2018, HALIFAX, NS

Consulted with the Manager of Service Delivery to plan and design application outline.

Created web application to help direct item donations from donors.

View completed donation search bar here:

https://halifax.bigbrothersbigsisters.ca/ways-to-give/clothing-donations/

4-H Nova Scotia / CRM Data Entry

(TEMPORARY) JANUARY 2018 - APRIL 2018, TRURO, NS

Completed a data entry project, assisting the organization to transition to a new Microsoft Dynamics CRM platform.

Jazz East / Volunteer (Multiple Positions)

2012 - 2018, HALIFAX, NS

Aided in the setup and teardown of the Halifax Jazz Festival.

Served customers and handled disputes as a bartender.

Managed multiple stages at Halifax Jazz & East Coast Music Festivals

Summerhill Group / Efficiency NS Representative

(TEMPORARY) OCTOBER 2016 - NOVEMBER 2016, HALIFAX, NS

Provided information on energy efficient products and services to engage and educate customers about Efficiency Nova Scotia.

Recorded and reported demonstration-related information, such as the number of questions asked by the audience, and the types of questions asked.

Almighty Software Company / Mobile Application

Developer/Board of Directors

APRIL 2016 - OCTOBER 2016, HALIFAX, NS

Created Start-up company and new social fitness application (KinSHIFT).

Learned Android system and wrote application to specifications decided in meetings.

Met with board of directors to decide business direction.